<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the King. A proclamation prohibiting the keeping of Bartholomew Faire, and Sturbridge Faire.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1625</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B12908</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 8792</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 506.h.11[50]</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99892585</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99892585</idno>
            <idno type="VID">185639</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B12908)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 185639)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C2:2[50])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the King. A proclamation prohibiting the keeping of Bartholomew Faire, and Sturbridge Faire.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
                  <author>Charles I, King of England, 1600-1649.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By I.L. and W.T. for Bonham Norton and Iohn Bill, printers to the Kings most excellent Maiestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Printed at Oxford :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1625.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Dated at end: Woodstocke the fourth day of August in the first yeare of his Maiesties raigne ..</note>
                  <note>Steele notation: Christian  his  yeare (italic).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Bartholomew Fair --  Law and legislation --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Plague --  Law and legislation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Charles I, 1625-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:185639:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>BY THE KING.</head>
            <head type="sub">A Proclamation prohibiting the keeping of Bartholomew Faire, and Sturbridge Faire.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>HE Kings moſt Excellent Maieſtie out of his Princely and Chriſtian care of his louing Subiects, that no good meanes of providence may bee neglected to ſtay the further ſpreading of the great infection of the Plague, doth finde it neceſſary to prevent all occaſions of publique con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſe of His people for the preſent, till it ſhall pleaſe Almighty God of his goodneſſe, to ceaſe the violence of the contagion, which is very farre diſperſed into many parts of the Kingdome already. And therefore remembring that there are at hand two Faires of ſpeciall note, vnto which there is vſually extraordinary reſort out of all parts of the Kingdome. The one kept in <hi>Smithfield</hi> neare the Citty of <hi>London,</hi> called <hi>Bartholomew Faire:</hi> and the other neare <hi>Cambridge,</hi> called <hi>Sturbridge Faire.</hi> The holding whereof at the vſuall times would in all likelyhood be the occaſion of fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther danger and infection to other parts of the Land, which yet by Gods mercy ſtand cleere, and free. Hath with the advice of his Maieſties Privie Councell, thought good by this open declaration of His pleaſure, and neceſſary commandment, not only to admoniſh and require all his louing Subiects to forbeare to reſort for this time to either of the ſaid two Faires, or to any other Faires within fifty miles of the ſaid Citty of <hi>London,</hi> but alſo to inioyne the Lords of the ſaid Faires, and others intereſſed in them, or any of them, that they all forbeare to hold the ſaid Faires, or any thing appertaining to them at the times ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſtomed, or at any other time, till by Gods goodneſſe and mercy the infection of the plague ſhall ceaſe, or be ſo much diminiſhed, that his Maieſtie ſhall giue order for holding them, vpon paine of ſuch puniſhment, as for a contempt, ſo much concerning the vni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſall ſafety of his people, they ſhall be adiudged to deſerue, which they muſt expect to be inflicted with all ſeverity, his Maieſties deſire being ſo intentiue for preventing the generall infection threatned, as he is reſolued to ſpare no man that ſhall be the cauſe of diſperſing the ſame. And to that purpoſe doth hereby further charge and enioyne vnder like pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty, all Cittizens, and Inhabitants of the ſaid Citty of <hi>London,</hi> that none of them ſhall repaire to any Faire held within any part of this Kingdome, vntill it ſhall pleaſe God to ceaſe the infection now reigning amongſt them, his Maieſties intention being, and ſo hereby declaring himſelfe, that no Lord of any Faires, or others intereſsed in the profits thereof, ſhall by this neceſſary and temporary reſtraint receiue any preiudice in the right of his, or their Faires, or liberties therevnto belonging, any thing before mentioned notwithſtanding. <hi>Given at the Court at Woodſtocke the fourth day of Auguſt in the firſt yeare of his Maieſties Raigne of great Brittaine, France, and Ireland.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>God ſaue the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed at Oxford by <hi>I. L.</hi> and <hi>W. T.</hi> for <hi>Bonham Norton</hi> and <hi>Iohn Bill,</hi> Printers to the Kings moſt Excellent Maieſtie. 1625.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
